

Skills

Technical skills I excel at: HTML & CSS, SCSS/LESS, Angular, Angular Material, Typescript, Javascript, Jest and Karma (unit testing), Node Package Management (npm). This is not a complete comprehensive list, as I am continuously learning new technologies, and have used many other tools throughout my career.

Proficient using Git, Git Hub, Atlassian tools (Confluence, JIRA, Bitbucket), as well as Adobe CS products.

Communication and analytical skills:

- Empathy and compassion
- Technical writing
- Attentive/Perceptive
- Reading body language
- Creative
- Desire to learn
- Innovative
- Resourceful
- Flexible

Leadership skills:

- Ownership
- Decision making
- Motivation and encouragement
- Able to prioritize and manage multiple tasks
- Mentoring
- Compromise

Education

UW-Milwaukee Sept. 2021-Present

BS Information Science & Technology

UW-Stout Sept. -Dec. 2019

BS Information Communications & Technology

Chippewa Valley Graduated Dec. 2015
Technical College

Associates Degree - Software Development

Emily Mikl



PHONE: 715-764-0283 | EMAIL: emilysmikl@gmail.com | emilymikl.dev

About Me

Front-end developer who is passionate about the user! Experience delivering delightful user experiences and beautiful, intuitive interfaces for enterprise-level software. Clear understanding of front-end technologies and frameworks, WCAG a11y standards, design system components and component libraries. Based out of Eau Claire, Wis. Experience working remotely as part of a team spread out across the United States.

Experience

Nelnet, Inc. (Formerly Great Lakes Higher Education) Jan. 2016-Present Lead developer for our corporate design system, Unifi. The Unifi Design System provides tested, accessible components that allow developers to build great user experiences. Prior to transitioning to our Unifi Design Studio UI/UX team, I was part of an Agile Scrum team, working closely with the UI/UX design team on the user experience for the apps we supported.

Some of my accomplishments at Nelnet include:

- Migrating our clients' marketing products to a CMS (Hubspot), which freed up our dev team to work on higher priority efforts.
- Leading our office remodel effort, which included gathering requirements, facilitating discussion and compromise, and working with our facilities team on the remodel plans and budget.
- Creating our Unifi Angular component library from scratch. You can view my components at work by visiting angular.unifi.nelnet.io.
- Evangelizing the usage of our Unifi Design System across the organization. Mentoring and teaching developers how to use it in their projects.

Mason Companies, Inc.

Aug. -Dec. 2015

Web Designer on Internet marketing team. Duties included designing and developing emails and content for company websites (nine total ventures and brands), and creating responsive email campaigns (design and code).

Great Lakes Higher Education

May-Aug. 2015

Completed a summer internship as a web design intern. Duties were project-based, and included graphic design for both print and web, front-end development using HTML, CSS and Javascript. Worked as part of a large Agile scrum team that included designers and developers.

Eau Claire Economic Development Corporation

May-Aug. 2014

Completed a summer internship as a front-end web developer on a community project. Created graphics for the website and altered the WordPress template with CSS and PHP.

Bloomer Advance, Inc.

May 2000-Mar. 2013

Thirteen years of working on a deadline as a desktop publisher/graphic designer. I led the initiative to switch to digital pagination, coordinating with the press company and training our internal staff. After getting our newspaper successfully switched over, I trained and successfully helped migrate our other four newspapers to digital pagination. I also led the initiative to publish our newspapers online, which eventually led to my career change into web development.